Ben John Dela Cruz

TV Director

Tallahassee, FL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ben-John-Dela-Cruz/05c883da59bc2dd6

I have a rich experience in Media and Television. I have been a Director, TV Actor, Documentary Segment Producer, Comedy Writer, Telenovela Writer, Music Video Director, and I am also a Photographer. I also go by "Bidz Dela Cruz" if you need to check me in IMDB.com.

I am a well-rounded person. I am not only artistic, I am also athletic and drug-free. I rarely get sick. I am a mountaineer, mountain biker and a rock climber. I used to be a competitive dragonboat rower, and powerlifter varsity in College. I am always active, hates to be late, and is not easily let down.

I have good analytical skills, I am a good team player with a very extrovert personality, I can easily adapt to situations, I can handle pressures properly, and I have the ability to negotiate with individuals. I am a member of the Tallahassee Mountain Bike Association, the local mountain biking group here. I have good telephone, computer and decision-making skills. I can also easily report to a Senior Producer. I also have a good command of the written language. Some of my written works can be found in the internet if you type in "Bidz Dela Cruz" in the google search box. Some of the websites I used to provide content are www.floridafishing.com, www.tuscany.com, www.nottinghill.com. For my most recent photography works, please follow the hashtag #CrimpfestProductions.

Willing to relocate to: New York, NY

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

TV, Movie, and Theater Actor

- June 1996 to Present

Music Video Director

Orlando - 2015 to 2015

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fPwC6YoMWbE

Director

Latest - 2013 to 2014

Guest Director

GMA NEWS TV - 2013 to 2014

Writer of Boy Pick-up, Mr. Assimo, and James Wang Segments

GMA NEWS TV - January 2012 to April 2013

Creator & Writer of Tata Lino

◆ Segment Producer (Tropang Potchi) (GMA-7) -- No longer connected

Writer (Bubble Gang)

GMA NEWS TV - 2012 to 2013

Floor Director

Game and Go - August 2011 to March 2012

Writer/Actor

Reputasyon - March 2011 to February 2012

Program Developer

Reality Seminar - 2012 to 2012

Writer/Actor

TV Portals - August 2010 to November 2011

I Laugh Sabado)

Creative Manager/Host/Actor (Smashbox Productions)

Techno Trip - February 2011 to March 2011

Writer (GMA-New Media)

Comedy Show - April 2010 to January 2011

Content writer

MyGMA.ph and WMN.ph - August 2009 to November 2009

contributor

Acting Workshop Facilitator and Trainor

The UP Repertory Company and UP Alay Sining Plays - September 2002 to September 2002

Acting Workshop for Modeling (Modelo Pilipinas, UP Hotel. April2 7 & 29, 2004), 2nd Acting Workshop for Modeling (Modelo Pilipinas, St. Vincent School. October 23, 24, 30, 31, November 6, 7, 13, 14, 2004), 3rd Acting Workshop for Modeling (Modelo Pilipinas. Harmony Bar, Annapolis St. July 29, August 5, August 12, 2006), Teatro Lakbay (1st Acting Workshop for the theater arm of Lakbay Kalikasan, August 2007), 1st Acting Workshop for Makati Med College of Nursing (Oct-Dec 2010), 1st Acting Workshop for Christians (Alta Rios Resort, Cavite. May 2013)

Goon in Agent Max Santiago

The UP Repertory Company and UP Alay Sining Plays - 1997 to 1997

in Kwek-Kwek, (Shorts 2004). Rapist in Danz Sport (Multi-awarded Short Film). Doctor in Mondo Manila, Award-winning Short Film, 1999). Played the role Badette in Joyce Bernal's The Anothers (Star Cinema), 2005. Had a guest appearance in Batad (Cinemalaya 2006), and had a cameo role in Tagapagligtas (Cinemalaya 2007). The Antagonist in 2009 Cinemalaya Movie: My Fake American Accent. Antagonist in 2010 Best Shorts: Kumot ng Panaginip. Bruno in 2011 Cinemalaya Best Shorts: Ang Umaatikabong Buhay ni Badong Aguirre. Gunman in Wala sa Gubat ang mga Hayop (Multi-awarded Short Film, 2014). Played the Director character in Kahit sa Anino (Short Film 2014)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Secondary Education

International Institute for Film 2013

College of Education, University of the Philippines 2004